RYAN N. VANDORP

5790 Cherrywood Dr, Apt 1706, West Bloomfield, MI 48322 | C: 248.762.5978 | E: ryanvandorp@gmail.com

SUMMARY

10+ years of experience in assorted technical projects and account management has provided me with a broad knowledge and understanding of the techniques and dedication required to produce high-quality deliverables. I've created and maintained various websites since my early college years, served as an account manager and sales engineer for an enterprise web hosting provider, and overseen website development and refined crucial CMS security protocols as a technical project manager.

HIGHLIGHTS

- Excellent Writing & Reporting Skills
- Technical Project Management Experience
- PHP Scripts/Software and SQL Knowledge
- LAMP (CentOS) Stack Development
- High Proficiency in WordPress & Other CMS
- Data Analysis, Excel & R / R Studio Familiarity
- Internet Marketing & SEO Skills
- Accustomed to Multi-Tasking in Team Settings

EXPERIENCE

Website Developer & Analyst

Independent Contractor - West Bloomfield, MI

Nov 2016 to Present

- Resumed part-time, referral work (remotely) following a family emergency during Fall of 2016.
- Developed sites and SE research campaigns for clients in Detroit and Vancouver.

Technical Project Manager Media Genesis – Troy, MI

July 2015 to August 2016

- Coordinated and managed the development process for multiple websites, applications, internet marketing and SEO campaigns
- Constructed website/app functionality documentation and diagrams, wireframes, and flow charts during the analysis and design phases of projects
- Researched and advised on utilization of optimal platforms, modules, and custom development for new clients and redesign projects for existing clients
- Lead and organized internal projects for improving routine security and maintenance of sites using open source CMS platforms (primarily WordPress and Drupal 6-7)

Account Manager | Sales Engineer

June 2012 to July 2015

- Servint Reston, VA
 - Addressed web hosting inquiries from prospects and assisted new clients in selecting optimal hosting products via email, live-chat, and phone
 - Provided ongoing support for existing clients, including resource utilization analysis, server upgrade and downgrade recommendations and migration coordination
 - Developed a custom sales management application, "ServInt Sales Pro," to increase efficiency by organizing frequently used resources and generating canned text for common sales tasks
 - Joined the "Enterprise Sales Team" in early 2014 and coordinated the provisioning of dedicated server solutions that required custom hardware configurations

Internet Marketing | Software Administrator Independent Contractor – Auburn Hills, MI

Sept 2006 to Dec 2011

- Developed and maintained the Oceanside Network forum using the vBulletin platform, and handled daily customer support functions (2009 – 2011)
- Created the Ponzi Scheme Alert organization, designed to provide free education and warnings to the general public about investment fraud and scams (2008-2012)
- Designed and implemented many blogs for public education, marketing promotion, and SEO research: Google Finance & Stocks, Pathetic America, and Hot Stock Opinions
- Built website marketing scripts and promotional "splash page" concepts for several clients and companies, such as: Nutronix International, ViaViente, Getaway Vacations, Eiro Research

EDUCATION

2011 Oakland University, School of Business Administration (Rochester, MI)

--- Bachelor of Science, Majors; Finance and Marketing (Cum Laude, Departmental Honors)